in this video I'll show you how to get
在本视频中，我将向
started with sculpting for complete
完全零基础的
beginners in blender so I'll show you
初学者展示如何在Blender中开始雕刻。我会演示
how you can set up blender for sculpting
如何设置Blender进行雕刻，
and then I'll be covering all the basic
然后介绍所有基本
tools and the basic brushes for
工具和笔刷。在
sculpting and then after I show you the
讲解完
basics of sculpting and blender we'll be
雕刻和Blender的基础知识后，我们将
doing a sculpting exercise by sculpting
通过雕刻
this cute fish character and then I'll
这个可爱的鱼形角色来进行雕刻练习。之后，我还会
also show you a cool painting option in
展示Blender雕刻模式下一个很棒的绘画选项，
blender sculpt mode where you can paint
你可以用它
some colors on the fish and if you'd
在鱼身上添加颜色。如果你
like to download these free project
想下载这个
files of the finished fish here then you
成品鱼的免费项目文件，
can download the project file for free
可以
on my gumroad store and my patreon page
在我的Gumroad商店和Patreon页面上免费下载。
I'll have the links in the description
链接就在视频描述中。
now if you've never used blender before
如果你以前从未使用过Blender，
and you're a complete beginner to
并且是Blender的完全新手，
blender then you may want to watch a
那么你可能需要观看一个
complete beginner tutorial series just
完整的入门教程系列，
to learn the very basics of the program
学习该程序的基础知识
and navigating around the program and
、操作方法、
the basic shortcut keys and basic 3D
基本快捷键和基本的3D
modeling so if you'd like to learn all
建模。 如果你想学习
the basics of blender then definitely
Blender的所有基础知识，那么一定要
check out my complete blender beginner
看看我的完整Blender入门
tutorial series it's a 14-part tutorial
教程系列，这是一个包含14个部分的教程
series and it's all completely free on
系列，在
my YouTube channel but in this video
我的YouTube频道上完全免费。不过，在这个视频中，
I'll just be covering the basics of the
我将只讲解
sculpting part blender and after you
Blender雕刻部分的基础知识。
watch this video if you find that you
看完这个视频后，如果你发现自己
really enjoy sculpting and you want to
真的很喜欢雕刻，并且想要
get more into sculpting then I can
更深入地学习，那么我
highly recommend checking out CG boost
强烈推荐你看看CG Boost的“
course Master 3D sculpting and blender
精通3D雕刻和Blender”课程。
so that's a much larger course on
这是一个内容更丰富的
sculpting and it goes into so much more
雕刻课程，讲解更加
depth into sculpting so in the course
深入。在这个课程中，
you'll learn all the sculpting Basics
你将学习所有雕刻基础知识，
like the different brushes the different
例如不同的笔刷、不同的
tools and sculpting workflows and the
工具和雕刻工作流程。
course also has some different beginner
课程中还有一些不同的入门
exercises which you can follow along to
练习，你可以跟着练习来
get better at sculpting you'll also
提高你的雕刻技巧。你还将
learn some cool Tech techniques for
学习一些很棒的技术，用于
creating base meshes for your sculpts
创建雕刻的基础网格。
and then the course covers the entire
课程还会涵盖
process of creating this cute creature
创建这个可爱生物
character so after this video If
角色的整个过程。所以，看完这个视频后…… 如果
sculpting is something that you want to
你想
get more into then I highly recommend
更深入地学习雕塑，我强烈推荐你
checking out the sculpting course by CG
看看CG Boost的雕塑课程。
boost and if you purchase the course
如果你
through my affiliate Link in the
通过我简介里的推广链接购买课程，
description then I'll earn a small
我会获得一小笔
commission so that's also a great way to
佣金，这也是
help support this channel now before we
支持本频道的好方法。在我们
get into sculpting I'd highly recommend
开始雕塑之前，我强烈建议你
using a drawing tablet if you're able to
使用绘图板（如果条件允许的话）。
because drawing tablets make sculpting
绘图板能让雕塑变得
so much easier and it can really improve
轻松许多，也能显著提升
your sculpt
你的雕塑水平。
now if you're just getting started with
如果你是
sculpting and you want to just try it
雕塑新手，只是想尝试一下，
out and see if you like sculpting then
看看自己是否喜欢雕塑，当然也
you can definitely use a mouse but it's
可以使用鼠标，但
much harder to sculpt with a mouse so
用鼠标进行雕塑难度要大得多。所以，
tablet if you're able to and so in this
如果条件允许，我强烈建议你使用绘图板。在这个
video I'm going to be using this small
视频里，我将使用这款
Walkin pad tablet so it's not anything
Walkin Pad小型绘图板。它并不
fancy it's not a display tablet or
花哨，也不是显示屏之类的，只是一个
which I can just plug into my computer
可以连接到电脑上的小型绘图板。
and then I look at my monitor and then
我看着显示器，然后就可以在
the pad tablet is down on my desk and I
绘图板上进行创作了。 我平时在桌子上
just sculpt using the pen and using a
用笔进行雕刻，但使用
drawing tablet is much better for
绘图板进行
sculpting because you're able to have a
雕刻效果更好，因为你可以保持
much better posture you're able to make
更好的姿势，
nice smooth Strokes with the pen and
用笔画出流畅的笔触。
most drawing tablets have pen pressure
大多数绘图板都支持压感，你
so you're able to use the pen pressure
可以利用压感
to make for instance the brush size
来调整笔刷
thicker or the brush strength stronger
粗细或笔触强度。
and if you're interested in purchasing a
如果你有兴趣购买
drawing tablet then I do have some
绘图板，我
Amazon links in the description to some
在描述中提供了一些
tablets that I recommend and those are
我推荐的亚马逊链接，这些是
affiliate links so if you purchase
联盟链接，如果你
something through those links then I'll
通过这些链接购买，我会
earn a small commission but with no
获得少量佣金，但你无需支付任何
extra cost to you now when you're doing
额外费用。现在，当你使用
sculpting and blender you need to start
Blender进行雕刻时，你需要
off with a high poly mesh for the
从高多边形模型开始。
sculpting because if I just hit the Tab
因为如果我按下Tab
Key to go into edit mode of this Cube
键进入这个立方体的编辑模式，
here when you're sculpting it pulls
雕刻时它会拖动
around the geometry of the mesh to
网格的几何体进行
actually sculpt the mesh so if I were to
实际雕刻。所以，如果我
try to sculpt with a very low poly
尝试用
object like this Cube I wouldn't be able
像这样的低多边形物体进行雕刻，我是无法成功雕刻的。
to sculpt much detail because this model
由于这个模型的多边形数量很少，所以很难雕刻出很多细节。
is so low poly because it has a Vertex
它只有一个顶点，
here and then another one here but it
然后是另一个顶点，
doesn't have any vertices in between
中间没有任何顶点。
them so what I'm going to do is press
因此，我要按
the a key to select everything in the
A 键选中场景中的所有物体，然后
scene and I'll hit X and let's just
按 X 键，再
click on delete so I'll now press shift
点击删除键。现在按 Shift+
a for the add menu and I'm going to go
A 打开添加菜单，向下滚动
down here to mesh and I'm just going to
到网格，
add an icosphere because an icosphere is
添加一个二十面体。二十面体
nice and smooth and round and it's very
光滑圆润，细节丰富。
detailed however you can see this is
但是，你可以看到这个模型的
kind of low poly so if I click right
多边形数量比较少。所以我点击
behind me on the add icosphere settings
身后的“添加二十面体设置”，
I'm going to click on the arrows here
点击这里的箭头
just to turn up the icosphere settings
来提高二十面体的设置。我把它
and I'm just going to turn up really
调到
high to like a seven if that's a bit
很高，比如 7。如果觉得有点卡顿，可以
laggy for you you don't have to turn up
不用调
that high but I'm going to turn up to a
这么高，但我调到
seven so it is nice and smooth and round
7 是为了让它光滑圆润。
and then I can click here to close the
然后点击这里关闭“
ad icosphere settings so now we can go
添加二十面体设置”。现在我们可以
to blender sculpt mode because right now
打开 Blender 了。
we are just in the object mode so there
我们现在处于物体模式，所以要切换到雕刻模式。
are two ways to get to blender sculpt
有两种方法可以进入Blender的雕刻
mode you can just select the object and
模式：你可以选择物体，
then you can click here in the corner
然后点击角落里的按钮，就可以在
and you can change it from object mode
物体模式和
of sculpt mode but what I prefer to do
雕刻模式之间切换。但我更喜欢
is to click right here to go to blender
点击这里进入Blender
sculpting workspace and this will
雕刻工作区，这样会
automatically take you into sculpt mode
自动进入
of the object that you have selected so
你所选物体的雕刻模式。
you can see right here it's taking us
你看，这里已经进入
into sculpt mode but it's also showing
雕刻模式了，而且还显示了
us now the different settings for
不同的
sculpting right here it has some more
雕刻设置。这里还有一些
settings up here for sculpting and then
雕刻设置，然后在
right over here you can see we have the
这里可以看到
panel with the brushes so I like to jump
笔刷面板。我喜欢跳转
to the sculpting workspace so
到雕刻工作区，这样
everything's already set up now just so
一切都设置好了。需要
you're aware all of these settings right
说明的是，
of these settings are the same settings
这里的所有设置和面板都是相同的，
which are right over here for example
例如，
you can see there is the radius and the
你可以看到半径和
strength so the radius is the size of
强度。半径是
your brush and the strength is how
笔刷的大小，强度是笔刷的
strong it is and those settings are also
力度。 这些设置也在
right here so we have the strength and
这里，包括强度和
also the radius then there's this D Topo
半径。这里是D Topo
setting right here and this setting is
设置，这个设置也在这里。
also right down here so these settings
这些设置
here and also the settings on the side
和侧面
panel are the same but then right over
板上的设置是一样的。
here on the left side we have all these
左边这里是各种
sculpting brushes now before we get into
雕刻笔刷。在介绍
the brushes I want to go over basic
笔刷之前，我想先讲解一下基本
navigation so I have my drawing tablet
操作。我的绘图板就在我
on my desk right in front of me and then
面前的桌子上，
I also have my keyboard a little bit
键盘则放在绘图
higher up above my tablet and I'm going
板上方一点的位置。我
to put my hand over the shift and
把手放在Shift和
control keys because the shift and
Ctrl键上，因为Shift和
control keys are very common buttons
Ctrl键是
that you'll use when you're sculpting
雕刻时常用的快捷键。
now you can change the settings of your
你可以
tablet in the driver settings or on the
在电脑的驱动程序设置或
graphics tablet settings on your
绘图板设置中更改绘图板的设置。
computer ever I've just left everything
我这里都保留了
at the default so the shortcut keys
默认设置，所以快捷键的功能
should work the same if you've just left
应该是一样的。
everything at the default now usually
通常
the tablet pens will come with a back
绘图板笔会有一个后退
button and a front button so to zoom in
按钮和一个前进按钮。要放大，
I'm going to hold down the control key
我按住Ctrl键，
and then click and drag with the front
然后点击并拖动前进
pen button now I'm not actually pressing
按钮。 实际上，我并
down with my tablet I'm not actually
没有用笔按压绘图板
pushing the pen down on the surface I'm
表面，而是将笔悬停在
just hovering my pen over the surface
表面上方，
and then I'm clicking with the front pen
然后点击笔头的按钮。
button so hold down the control key and
按住 Ctrl 键，
then click with the front pen button
然后点击笔头的
button and you can click and drag to
按钮。你可以点击并拖动来
zoom in and out but again my pen is just
放大和缩小。再次强调，我的笔只是
hovering over the surface but it's not
悬停在表面上方，并没有
actually pressing down on the drawing
真正按压绘图
tablet now if you don't hold down the
板。如果你不按住
control key and you just click with the
Ctrl 键，只是点击笔头的按钮，画面就会围绕它
front pen button that is going to orbit
旋转，
around so I can look around the sphere
这样我就可以环顾四周。
now if you hold down the shift key and
如果你按住 Shift 键，
then click and drag with the front pen
然后点击并拖动笔头的
button that is going to pan around so I
按钮，画面就会平移，这样我就
can move over here to the right side and
可以向右移动，
move around here to the left side now
向左移动。
another way to zoom around your sculpt
另一种缩放雕刻区域的方法
is to hold down the ALT key and then
是按住 Alt 键，然后
just click with the front pen button and
点击笔头的按钮。
you can see wherever I'm clicking that's
你可以看到，无论我点击哪里，画面都会放大
going to kind of zoom over to that area
到那个区域。
now to actually sculpt on the digital
现在，在数字黏土上进行实际雕刻时，
clay we're not actually going to use the
我们实际上不会使用
pen buttons we're actually going to
笔头的按钮，而是会按下笔头的按钮。
press down on our tablet so you can just
在平板电脑上，您可以
click and then just drag around and then
点击并拖动，然后
press down on your tablet and it's going
按住平板电脑，即可
to add clay now once you've sculpted on
添加黏土。雕刻完成后，
an area if you want to zoom into that
如果您想放大该区域，可以按
on the keyboard and that's going to zoom
键盘上的句号键（.），即可放大
into that specific area so if I want to
到该区域。例如，如果我想
like sculpt over here I can sculpt there
在这里雕刻，只需
by just pressing down on the tablet and
按住平板电脑，
then hit the period key and you can see
然后按句号键，即可放大到该位置。
location so if I just orbit around by
如果我
clicking with the front pen button and
点击笔尖按钮，
then just moving my pen over the Tablet
然后在平板电脑表面移动笔，
Surface you can see we've zoomed into
可以看到我们已经放大到
that area so again if I just press down
该区域。同样，如果我按住
on the tablet and draw that is going to
平板电脑并绘制，即可
add clay now if you want to get rid of
添加黏土。如果您想移除
clay so if you want to push the clay
黏土，也就是将黏土推
back in instead of pulling it out you
回而不是拉出，
can hold down the control key so if I
可以按住 Ctrl 键。如果我
hold down the control key and then just
按住 Ctrl 键，然后在
sculpt here you can see it's pushing in
这里雕刻，可以看到它是将
the clay instead of bringing it out now
黏土推回而不是拉出。
if you don't want to hold down the
如果您不想按住 Ctrl
control control key you can instead
键，也可以…… 你也可以
click on the minus button so now that
点击减号按钮。现在
it's set to the minus button if I just
它被设置为减号按钮，如果我
click and sculpt along here you can see
点击并沿着这里雕刻，你可以看到
it's going to push in the clay then if I
它会把黏土压进去。然后如果我
click back here to the plus now I can
点击这里回到加号按钮，我就可以
just sculpt and it's going to bring out
雕刻，它会把
the clay so let's now go over the
黏土拉出来。现在我们来看看
different brushes so I'm not going to go
不同的笔刷。我不会
over every single brush because this is
讲解每一个笔刷，因为这是
a beginner tutorial and there's no point
一个入门教程，没必要让
in overwhelming you with all the brushes
你被所有的笔刷搞得眼花缭乱。
most of the brushes I actually don't use
实际上，我大部分笔刷都不用，
that I use most of the time so I'll just
我最常用的可能只有五六个。所以我只会讲解
be going over the main brushes that I
我
think you need to know now the brush
认为你需要知道的主要笔刷。
which is on default here is the draw
默认的笔刷是绘图
brush and if you want to make this
笔刷。如果你想放大它，以便
bigger so you can see all the names of
看到所有笔刷的名称，
the brushes you can click and drag out
你可以点击并拖动
here in the corner and that is going to
角落里的鼠标，这样就能
make it bigger and now you can see
放大它。现在你可以看到
there's all the different names of the
所有不同的
brushes or if you want to collapse them
笔刷名称了。如果你想折叠它们，
you can click and drag and make this
你可以点击并拖动鼠标
smaller you can also make it really
缩小它。
small if you just want to have one row
如果你只想用一排
brushes or you can completely close it
笔刷，可以把窗口调得很小，或者完全关闭它。
but I'll just leave this how it is I
但我还是保持这样吧，我
like how it is with two rows of brushes
喜欢两排笔刷的样子。
so the first one here is the draw brush
第一个是绘图笔刷，
and this is the default brush and you
这是默认笔刷。你
can see it's just going to make a little
可以看到它只会画出一小团
blob of clay kind of like a little hump
黏土，有点像一个小凸起。
there there now the next most common
接下来你最常用的
brush that you'll probably use is the
笔刷可能是
clay strips brush and the clay strips
黏土条笔刷。黏土条
brush is basically going to add layers
笔刷基本上是用来添加
of clay now I also want to show you the
黏土层的。现在我还想给你展示一下
strength and the radius because you can
强度和半径，因为你可以
see this this is kind of small right now
看到这个笔刷现在有点小。
so right here you have the strength so
这里是强度调节，
you can drag this up and down so if I
你可以上下拖动它。如果我
turn it way up all the way to one now if
把它调到最大，也就是 1，那么在
I sculpt here you can see it's going to
这里雕刻，你可以看到力度会
be a lot stronger or if I make this
强很多。如果我把它调
really low now if I sculpt here you can
得很低，那么在这里雕刻，你可以
see it's barely adding any detail so
看到几乎没有添加任何细节。所以
I'll turn this up pretty high maybe I'll
我把它调高一些，比如调到
turn this up to like a 7 so it's kind of
7，这样力度就
stronger then we also have the radius
强一些了。这里还有半径调节，
here so I can drag up the radius and now
我可以…… 向上拖动半径，现在
if I start to go along here you can see
如果我沿着这条线走，你可以看到
we're adding in much larger layers of
我们正在添加更大的
clay now there is shortcut keys for the
黏土层。现在半径和强度都有快捷键，
radius and the strength so if you press
所以如果你按下
the F key then you can drag your pen
F 键，就可以拖动笔刷
bigger or smaller and then just click to
变大或变小，然后点击
confirm that and that's going to change
确认，这样就能改变
the size of the brush so F make it
笔刷的大小。所以按 F 键可以把笔刷调得很
really big click and then you can just
大，点击一下，然后你就可以
sculpt along there now the radius is
沿着这条线雕刻了。半径是
shift F so if you press shift F now you
Shift+F，所以如果你按下 Shift+F，你
can see it's going to show you how
可以看到这里会显示笔刷的
strong it is by this number here and
强度（用这个数字表示）和颜色
also how dark it is so if I turn it like
深浅。如果我把它调到最大（比如
all the way up to one now you can see
1），你可以看到
the strength is going to be a lot bigger
强度会大很多。
or again if I press shift F I can make
或者，如果我再按一次 Shift+F，我可以把
this really small maybe just like a 0.1
它调得很小，比如 0.1，
and now you can see it's going to be
现在你可以看到效果会
very subtle so again F to change the
非常微妙。所以，F 键改变笔刷
size and shift F to change the radius
大小，Shift+F 键改变半径。
but if that's too hard to remember you
如果这些快捷键太难记，你也
can easily just change the strength and
可以直接在这里调整笔刷的强度和
the radius right here now while we're
半径。现在我们来
talking about the strength and the
谈谈笔刷的强度和
radius I also want to talk about the pen
半径，我还想谈谈笔
pressure so most tablets will come with
压。大多数数位板…… 它带有
a pen pressure so basically that is a
压感功能，也就是
sensitivity in the pen which is going to
笔的灵敏度，可以
detect how hard you are pressing the pen
检测你按压笔尖
down on the tablet and this is another
在绘图板上的力度。这也是
reason why using a drawing tablet is so
为什么使用绘图板进行雕刻
much better than using a mouse for
比使用鼠标好得多的原因之一，
sculpting because you can use the pen
因为你可以使用压
pressure now if you click on this button
感功能。点击这里的按钮即可
here that is going to turn on the pen
开启压
pressure so right now we'll just leave
感功能。现在我们先
it on here for the strength so now that
开启它，看看力度如何。
the pen pressure is enabled if I just
启用压感功能后，如果我
push down really lightly you can see
轻轻按压，可以看到
it's only adding a little bit of clay
只添加了一点点黏土；
but if I push down really hard now you
但如果我用力按压，可以
can see it's adding a lot more clay and
看到添加了更多的黏土。
if I just make my brush a bit smaller
如果我把笔刷调小一点（我放大一下画面），
let me zoom out here I can start by
我可以先
pressing down really lightly and then I
轻轻按压，然后
can slowly press down harder and harder
慢慢加重，
and you can see it's going to be really
可以看到
strong and then I can slowly press down
力度越来越大；再慢慢减轻，力度也越来越小。这个功能
get less strong so that's super useful
非常实用。
let's turn this off by clicking on this
点击这个
button now the other one is the radius
按钮即可关闭压感功能。另一个功能是半径调节，
so if I click on this button here
点击这里的按钮
that'll turn on the pen pressure and now
即可开启半径调节。 笔压控制，现在
if I start to sculpt here you can see
如果我开始在这里雕刻，你可以看到
it's really small and then if I press
它非常小，然后如果我用力
down harder you can see It'll get much
按压，你可以看到它会变
bigger and then I can press down just a
大很多，然后我轻轻按压，
little bit and it'll get much smaller so
它又会变小很多。
this is useful for making really nice
这对于制作非常漂亮、
organic looking Strokes now usually when
自然的笔触非常有用。通常
I'm sculpting I like to have the radius
我在雕刻时喜欢
turned off but I like to have the
关闭半径，但
strength turned on that's just how I
打开力度，这只是我的个人习惯。当然
like it but you could also turn on both
你也可以同时打开
of them and if you turn on both of them
它们。如果同时打开，
when you press down harder it'll get
当你用力按压时，笔触会变得更
stronger and bigger and if you press
粗更大，而当你轻轻
down lighter then it'll get smaller and
按压时，笔触会变得更细更小。
less strong so you can definitely do
所以你完全可以根据自己的
that if you want to you can really do
喜好来设置，在
sculpting you can also turn them on and
雕刻过程中，你可以
off depending on what you're working on
根据正在处理的内容随时打开或关闭它们。
but I'm going to keep the radius turned
但我这次会保持半径
off and the strength turned on all right
关闭，力度打开。好的，
so let's go back over the brushes now so
现在我们再来看看笔刷。
the next brush that I want to show you
接下来我要展示的
is the crease brush this is a super
是褶皱笔刷，这是一个非常
common one so if I just zoom in here
常用的笔刷。如果我 放大一下，
let's say that I want to make a bit of a
假设我想在这里做出一点褶皱，
crease here let me just make my brush
我把笔刷调
bigger I can just go along here and you
大一点，就可以沿着这里画了。你
can see it's basically going to pinch in
可以看到，它基本上会把
the clay and kind of add a crease there
黏土捏进去，在这里形成一个褶皱。
so I can just go along here and kind of
所以我可以沿着这里画，在
add a nice crease there now if you want
这里做出一个漂亮的褶皱。如果你
to bring it out instead you can again
想让它凸出来，可以在雕刻的时候
hold down the control key as you are
按住Ctrl键。
sculpting and when you hold down the
当你再次按住
control key again just like I showed you
Ctrl键时，就像我刚才演示的
for the draw brush it's going to do the
绘图笔刷一样，它会产生
opposite effect so you can see if I'm
相反的效果。你可以看到，如果我
holding down the control key instead of
按住Ctrl键，它不会把褶皱捏进去，而是会把黏土捏出来，
pinch it out and make like a little
形成一个小小的
sharp bump there and the same thing
凸起。
works for the clay strips brush if I
黏土条笔刷也是如此。如果我
just normally sculpt it'll sculpt out
正常雕刻，它会向外雕刻；
but if I hold down the control key you
但如果我按住Ctrl键，你
can see it's going to sculpt in let's go
可以看到它会向内雕刻。我们
to another Super common brush which is
来看另一个非常常用的笔刷——
the smooth brush and this is super
平滑笔刷，它在
useful for smoothing out your sculpt
雕刻完成后用来平滑表面非常有用。
after you've sculpted because you can
你已经雕刻好了，因为你可以
see right here if you kind of zoom in
看到，如果你放大一点，
you can see all the topology there and
就能看到所有的拓扑结构，
it maybe looks a little bit rough so let
它看起来可能有点粗糙，所以
me just make my radius bigger so now I
我把半径调大一些，现在我
can just lightly go along here using
可以用平滑笔刷轻轻地沿着这里涂抹。
that smooth brush you can see it's going
你可以看到它会把
to smooth out the clay and make it look
黏土表面抹平，让它看起来
a lot nicer now the smooth brush is so
更漂亮。平滑笔刷非常
commonly used that there's actually a
常用，所以它有一个
shortcut for it now there are actually
快捷键。实际上，
shortcuts for all the brushes if you
所有笔刷都有快捷键，如果你把
just hover your mouse over the brushes
鼠标悬停在笔刷上，
you can see it's going to show you a
就会显示
shortcut so you can see like this one
快捷键。你可以看到，像这样的笔刷的
the shortcut is V so if I hit V that'll
快捷键是 V，所以如果我按下 V，就会
go to the draw brush and there's
切换到绘图笔刷。
different shortcut keys for all of them
每个笔刷都有不同的快捷键，
I usually just click over here to click
我通常点击这里来选择
on each one of the brushes however the
每个笔刷。但是
smooth brush is used so often that if
平滑笔刷非常常用，所以如果
you hold down the shift key that's going
你按住 Shift 键，它会
to automatically switch over to the
自动切换到
smooth brush and then if you let go of
平滑笔刷；然后如果你松开
the shift key that'll remove the smooth
Shift 键，它就会移除平滑
brush and bring it back to the brush
笔刷，切换回
that you were using before so for
你之前使用的笔刷。
example let's say I'm using clay strips
例如，假设我…… 我用的是黏土条
brush I'm going to go along here and I'm
笔刷，接下来我要在这里
just going to sculpt some layers of clay
雕刻几层黏土。
so let's say I want to smooth this out
假设我想让它更平滑一些，与其
well instead of clicking here to the
点击这里切换到平滑笔刷，不如
smooth brush I can just hold down the
按住
shift key and it will automatically turn
Shift键，它会自动将
my brush into the smooth brush and I can
笔刷切换到平滑笔刷。然后我可以
go along here and just smooth it out but
沿着这里移动，把它平滑一些。但是
then as soon as I let go of the shift
一旦我松开Shift
key it'll go back to the brush that I
键，它就会切换回我
was using before so I can add a bunch of
之前使用的笔刷。所以我可以在这里添加一些
clay here hold down the shift key and
黏土，按住Shift键，
then just lightly go along here and kind
然后轻轻地沿着这里移动，把
of smooth it out and then I can just go
它平滑一些。之后我就可以切换
back to using the clay strips brush now
回黏土条笔刷了。
another common brush that you might use
另一个你可能会用到的常用笔刷
is the inflate brush and this is going
是膨胀笔刷，它的作用正如其
to do exactly what the name says so if I
名。如果我沿着
just go along here you can see it's
这里移动，你可以看到它
basically going to inflate whatever I'm
基本上会膨胀我正在雕刻的任何东西，使它变得
lumpy and kind of popping it out now
凹凸不平，有点鼓胀的感觉。
another cool brush that you might use a
另一个你可能会经常用到的很棒的笔刷
lot is the scrapes brush so for this let
是刮擦笔刷。所以，
me again just make my brush a bit bigger
我再把笔刷调大一点。
so I'll press the F key make it bigger
我按F键放大，
so with the scrapes brush it's basically
这样用刮擦笔刷就能把黏土
going to flatten it out and kind of
刮平，就像刮掉一些黏土一样。
scrape away the clay so if I want to
如果我想让表面
make this smooth you can see if I go
光滑，你可以看到，我沿着这条线移动，就像是在把
scraping away the clay and making little
黏土刮平，刮掉一些
sharp points so I can just go along here
尖锐的点。所以我可以沿着这条线移动，把这些尖锐的点推开，把它们都刮平，
away the clay and then another Super
刮掉一些黏土。还有一个超级
useful brush this is a really common one
好用的笔刷，非常常用，就是
is the grab brush and I do use the grab
抓取笔刷。我经常用抓取
brush a lot and so the grab brush is
笔刷，它就在这里。抓取笔刷的
really easy to remember the shortcut the
快捷键很容易记住，
shortcut key is the G key so just hit G
是G键，所以按G键
for grab that'll go to the grab brush
就能切换到抓取笔刷。
and for the grab brush it's usually
使用抓取笔刷时，
better if your brush is really big so
笔刷越大越好。
with the grab brush instead of it
抓取笔刷不是
sculpting the clay it's going to pull
雕刻黏土，而是拉扯
around the clay so if I kind of Zoom way
黏土。如果我把画面放大，
out here make my brush really big you
笔刷调大，你
can see I can pull the clay around so
可以看到我可以拉扯黏土。
this is super useful just for moving
这非常实用。
around the clay and changing the
移动黏土并改变
proportions of your sculpt so if you're
雕塑的比例，例如，如果您正在
sculpting something like a face and then
雕刻一张脸，然后
you realize maybe the proportions are a
发现比例可能有点
bit off or maybe when you're first
不对劲；或者，当您刚
starting your sculpt if you just want to
开始雕刻时，只是想
play around with the base mesh you can
调整一下基础网格，您可以
just kind of pull this around and this
拖动这个
brush is very useful now another useful
笔刷，它非常实用。另一个有用的
brush which is similar to the grab brush
笔刷类似于抓取笔刷，
but it is a bit different is the snake
但又略有不同，那就是蛇
hook brush so if I change this over to
钩笔刷。如果我切换到
the snake hook now if I just click and
蛇钩笔刷，点击并
drag here you can see it's similar to
拖动这里，您可以看到它类似于
the grab brush but instead of it pulling
抓取笔刷，但它不会拖动
around a large area it's just going to
大片区域，而是
pull around this small area and I can
拖动一小块区域，我可以把这部分
kind of pop out this area maybe bring
区域凸出来，或者把
this out so it's going to kind of make
它拉出来，这样就能形成类似
sort of like a snake shape now another
蛇的形状。另一个
you'll probably use a lot is the
您可能经常会用到的非常有用的雕刻功能是
symmetry so I've just brought back this
对称性。我刚刚恢复了
original ecosphere here and let's say
最初的生态球模型，假设
that you're sculpting like a face or a
您正在雕刻一张脸、一个
character or something which is
角色或其他
symmetrical and if you want one side to
对称的物体，如果您想要一个 将一侧
be mirrored over to the other side what
镜像到另一侧 w
you can do is click on these buttons
你可以点击这里的按钮，
here so these are the Symmetry settings
这些是对称设置。
you can see it kind of looks like a
你可以看到它看起来像一只
butterfly there and the most common one
蝴蝶，最常用的
you're going to use is the X so if I
是 X 轴对称。如果我
turn on the X symmetry now you can see
现在开启 X 轴对称，你可以看到
as I move move my brush here you can see
当我移动笔刷时，
there's a little blue dot here and then
这里有一个小蓝点，
other side showing you where it's going
另一侧也有一个小蓝点，它们显示了
to mirror so if I was sculpting a face
镜像的位置。如果我在这里雕刻一张脸，
here you can see it's going to mirror on
你可以看到它会在
the other side so that's how you can add
另一侧镜像。这就是在
symmetry when you are sculpting a
雕刻
character or a creature or really
角色、生物或
anything which is symmetrical and you
任何对称物体时添加对称的方法。你
can also turn on the X1 and the y1 if
也可以根据需要开启 X1 和 Y1 轴对称。
you want to as well you can see that's
你可以看到，这将
going to add the Symmetry on the X Y and
在 X、Y 和
Z AIS but for most things you're
Z 轴上添加对称。但对于大多数情况，你
probably just going to use the xaxis to
可能只会使用 X 轴来来回
symmetrize it back and forth now this
对称。这种情况
happens for me a lot let's say I'm
经常发生在我身上。假设我正在
sculpting a face or something and I'm
雕刻一张脸或其他东西，然后我……
going to start to sculpt the eye and
开始雕刻眼睛的时候，
then I realize that I forgot to turn on
我突然意识到我忘了开启
the Symmetry well what you can do is
对称模式。你可以
click on this little drop- down arrow
点击这里的小下拉箭头，
right here and then there is a symmetri
然后会看到一个对称
setting and you can see there is a
设置，里面有个
direction and most of the time you can
方向选项。大多数情况下，你可以
just leave it at Negative X to positive
直接把它设置成从负 X 到正
X or you might need to change it from
X，或者你可能需要把它从
positive X to Negative X but I'm just
正 X 到负 X 改成正 X。不过我先保持
click on the symmetrize button and what
默认设置，然后点击“对称化”按钮。这个按钮的作用是把这一侧的 X 轴
on this side and then it mirrored it
镜像
over to the positive X which is over on
到另一侧的正 X 轴上。
this side and then of course click on
当然，点击
the x button here to turn on the ex
这里的 X 按钮开启双侧对称，
symetry and then you can continue to
这样你就可以继续
sculpt your character and it will mirror
雕刻角色了，它会把模型镜像
it over to the other side now I
到另一侧。我
mentioned this earlier in the video but
在视频前面提到过，
if you have a very low poly mesh and you
如果你有一个低多边形模型，并且
try to sculpt with this let me just add
尝试用这个模型雕刻，比如我在
a cube here and go to sculpt mode you
这里添加一个立方体，然后进入雕刻模式，你
can see if I try to sculpt this I can't
会看到如果我尝试雕刻这个立方体，我
really add much detail here even if I go
几乎无法添加任何东西。 这里有个细节：即使我使用
to the clay strips brush and start to
黏土条笔刷，开始在
add clay here start to sculpt you can
这里添加黏土并开始雕刻，你会
see it's not really doing anything
发现它
except on the edges and that is because
除了边缘之外几乎没有任何变化。这是因为
this is a very low polymer mesh so you
这是一个低多边形网格，所以你
need a very high poly mesh like this
需要一个高多边形网格，就像这个
object here it's very high poly because
物体一样。这个物体的多边形数量非常多，因为
the sculpt mode actually moves around
雕刻模式实际上会移动
the geometry of the mesh but usually
网格的几何体。但通常情况下，在
when you're sculpting you're going to
雕刻过程中，你
need to add more geometry as you're
需要不断添加几何体。比如说，
sculpting because let's say I'm going to
我要把这个
pull out the mesh here let's just drag
网格拖出来，我们把
this up here let's say I'm maybe making
它拖到这里。假设我正在给
a limb on a character or something you
角色制作肢体之类的东西，你
can see as I pull this out here using
可以看到，当我使用
the snake hook brush you can see the
蛇钩笔刷把它拖出来时，
geometry is being all stretched out if I
几何体都被拉伸了。如果我
hit the Tab Key to go into edit mode you
按下 Tab 键进入编辑模式，你
can see the vertices and faces are being
可以看到顶点和面都被
really stretched so as you're sculpting
拉伸得很厉害。所以在雕刻过程中，
you're going to need to add more
你需要不断添加几何
geometry as you sculpt and there's two
体。有两种
different ways to do that and those two
不同的方法可以做到这一点，这两个
settings are right up here so there is
设置就在这里。 所以这里有
the DPO and there is the remesh and I'll
DPO和重新网格化工具，我会
show you how to use both of them so
演示如何使用它们。
first let's go over the remesh so you
首先我们来看看重新网格化工具。你
can remesh the sculpt as you are
可以在雕刻的同时重新网格化模型，
sculpting and it's going to smooth out
它会平滑几何体，使几何体更加均匀。假设
the geometry so let's say that I want to
我想给
add more detail to this because if I
这个模型添加更多细节，比如，如果我
like go here to the clay strips brush
选择粘土条笔刷，
and then I start to sculpt here you can
然后开始雕刻，你可以
see because all the faces are really
看到，由于所有面都被
stretched it just looks really warped
拉伸得很厉害，看起来非常扭曲
and weird so what I can do is I can
和奇怪。这时我可以
press the r key and when I press the r
按下R键，按下R
key a grid is going to show up and I can
键后会出现一个网格，我可以来回
drag my pen back and forth and this will
拖动笔刷来
change the size of the remesh so I'll
改变重新网格化工具的大小。我把
just make it a bit smaller and then just
它缩小一点，然后
click to place that there now I haven't
点击放置。现在我还没有重新网格化，所以要重新网格化，
I can press crlr and controlr is going
我可以按下Ctrl+R，Ctrl+R会重新网格
to remesh the sculpt so you can see the
化模型。你可以看到，
sculpt still retains its shape however
模型仍然保留了它原有的几何形状。 虽然形状有所改变，但
it's given lots more detail to the
它为几何体增添了更多细节。
geometry so now if I start to sculp here
现在，如果我开始在这里雕刻，
you can see the geometry is nice and
你可以看到几何体光滑细腻，
smooth and that looks much better if I
看起来好多了。如果我
press the r key again and like drag this
再次按下 R 键，然后拖动这个
grid here and make it really small and
网格并将其缩小，
then press controlr you can see it's
再按下 Ctrl+R，你可以看到它将
going to be really low poly so this is a
变成一个低多边形模型。这是一个
really great workflow using the remesh
非常棒的工作流程，利用了重新网格化功能。在
so as you're sculpting you can
雕刻过程中，你可以
occasionally press the r key make it
偶尔按下 R 键来增加
more detailed then press controlr to
细节，然后按下 Ctrl+R 进行
remesh it and then you can add more
重新网格化，之后你可以根据需要添加更多
detail as you need it so that's a really
细节。这是一个
great workflow another really great
非常棒的工作流程。另一个非常棒的
workflow to sculpting is the D toppo and
雕刻工作流程是 D Toppo。D
the D toppo will add add more geometry
Toppo 会在你雕刻的过程中添加更多几何体。
as you're sculpting so if you're just
因此，如果你
sculpting in a specific spot and you're
正在雕刻某个特定区域，并且雕刻的是一个
sculpting a really detailed area it's
非常精细的区域，它就会
just going to add more detail to that
为该区域添加更多细节。
area so to show you I'm going to press
为了演示，我将按下
the r key make this a bit smaller and
R 键将其缩小一些，
then I'll press controlr and it's going
然后按下 Ctrl+R 进行重新网格化。
individual faces now well if I click on
现在你可以看到所有单独的面了。如果我点击
this check mark here and then I just
这里的勾号，然后
need to click on okay that is going to
点击确定，就能
turn the D too on so with the DPO if you
启用DPO（细节对象）。在DPO中，如果你
click right here on the drop down you
点击这里的下拉菜单，
can see there's going to be a detail
可以看到有一个细节
size so for example I'll just turn this
大小的选项。例如，我现在把它设为
to like a six for now so now if I start
6。现在，如果我开始
to sculpt here you can see it's adding
雕刻，可以看到
more geometry as I sculpt if I hold down
随着雕刻的进行，几何体也在不断增加。如果我按住
the Z button that's going to bring up
Z键，就会弹出
this Pi menu and I can move my mouse
π菜单，然后我可以把鼠标移到
over to wireframe and then let go you
线框模式，再松开鼠标。你
can also just click on this button here
也可以点击这里的按钮
to go to wireframe and you can see
切换到线框模式。你可以看到
here's the geometry of the mesh but
这里是网格的几何体，但
where I've sculpted you can see it's
我雕刻过的地方
much more detailed and if I just sculpt
细节更多了。如果我继续雕刻，
more and more maybe zoom in a bit and
也许可以放大一点，
then sculpt more and more you can see
然后再继续雕刻，你可以看到细节
it's going to be much more detailed if I
会更加丰富。如果我
hit the Tab Key to go into edit mode and
按Tab键进入编辑模式，然后
let's just go back to solid view you can
回到实体视图，可以
see now it's more detailed where we have
看到现在细节更丰富了。 我们之前
sculpted because of that D toppo but
因为使用了D拓扑而进行了雕刻，但这里
then right over here it's lower detailed
细节较少，
so let's go back into sculpt mode and
所以我们回到雕刻模式。
you can see it actually turned the D
可以看到，它实际上关闭了D
Topo setting off so I need to click on
拓扑设置，所以我需要点击
this check mark here and then click on
这里的勾选标记，然后点击确定。
okay and then of course that detail is
当然，细节
also controlled by the detail size so
也受细节大小控制。
let's say I want to make this much less
假设我想让
detailed so let's turn this detail size
细节更少，我们就把细节大小
to like a 10 now if I sculpt here you
调到10。现在如果我在这里雕刻，
can see the detail is a lot smaller
可以看到细节少了很多，
there is less detail because I've turned
因为我提高了细节大小。
that size up so if you turn this detail
如果把细节
size down to a smaller number then the
大小调小，
faces are going to be smaller now I
面也会变小。我之前
mentioned that if you zoom in closer and
提到过，如果放大
then sculpt there's going to be more
再雕刻，
detail well that is controlled by this
细节会更多。这是由
setting right here the relative detail
相对细节这个设置控制的。
so if I click on the relative detail and
如果我点击相对细节，然后把
then change it to constant detail
它改成恒定细节，
instead now I can zoom in and I can
现在我可以放大并
sculpt and you can see it's super low
雕刻，可以看到细节非常少。
detail so on the DPO settings I need to
所以在D拓扑设置中，我需要
change this resolution so I'm just going
更改分辨率，我只需要把它
to turn this resolution to like a 30
调小。 现在我把分辨率调到 30 左右，进行
instead now I sculpt here you can see
雕刻。你可以看到
it's adding a detail level of 30 but if
它添加了 30 级的细节。但是如果
I zoom really far out and then sculpt
我把视图拉得很远再雕刻，
you can see the detail level is still
你会发现细节级别仍然保持
going to be the same or if I zoom in
不变；或者如果我把视图拉
really really close and then sculpt you
得很近再雕刻，你
can see the detail level is the same so
会发现细节级别也保持不变。这
that is because we've set the detailing
是因为我们在这里把细节设置
here to constant detail but I like
成了恒定细节。但我
relative detail better because if I'm
更喜欢相对细节，因为如果我
sculpting a really detailed area I can
雕刻的是一个非常精细的区域，我可以把
turn it to relative detail and that way
它改成相对细节。这样，
if I zoom in that area is going to be
如果我放大，这个区域的细节就会
more detailed and then if I zoom in more
更多；如果我继续放大，
it'll be even more detailed but then if
细节会更多；但如果
I zoom really far away it's going to be
我把视图拉得很远，细节就会
less Det detailed so that is super
减少。所以
useful using the D too feature so you
使用 D Too 功能非常有用。你
can really use whichever method you like
可以使用任何你喜欢的方法，比如
you can use the remesh or the D too and
使用重网格或 D Too。
as you get better at sculpting you'll
随着你雕刻技巧的提高，你会
find that sometimes some places are
发现有些地方更
better for the remesh and others are
适合使用重网格，而有些地方更
better for the D toppo so now that I've
适合使用 D Too。现在我已经讲解完了
gone over the basic brushes and the
基本笔刷。 接下来，我们来学习一些
basic tools let's do a sculpting
基本工具，
exercise by sculpting the cute fish
通过雕刻一条可爱的鱼来练习一下雕刻技巧。
character so I'm just going to click
我点击
right back here to go to the layout and
这里返回布局界面，这样就能回到
that'll take us back to object node and
对象节点。
we can just delete this practice object
我们可以删除这个练习对象，
and let's now Model A a base mesh for
现在来建模鱼的基础网格。
the fish so I'm first going to press
首先，我按
shift C to make sure that this 3D cursor
Shift+C，确保3D光标
here is in the center of the scene so
位于场景中心。然后，
I'll now go to the add menu and I'm just
我打开添加菜单，
going to add a cube and I will hit the
添加一个立方体。按
Tab Key to go into edit mode and I'm
Tab键进入编辑模式，
going to go to the face select and I'll
选择面，选中立方体的正面，按
will hit e to extrude we're just going
E键挤出。我们先挤出立方体的正面，
bit and then extrude out again and kind
然后再挤出一次，缩小
of scale it down and then bring it down
它的尺寸，然后沿
on the z-axis and bring it over on the Y
Z轴向下移动，沿Y轴向右移动。
AIS let's now hit tab to go back to
现在按Tab键返回
object mode and I'll press control 2 to
对象模式，按Ctrl+2
add a sub division surface with two
添加一个两级细分曲面。 打开
levels and I'll use the object context
对象上下文
menu and click on shade smooth you can
菜单，点击“平滑着色”。你
also click on object and then click on
也可以直接点击对象，然后点击“
shade smooth right there and I'll hit
平滑着色”。我按
tab to go back into edit mode and I'm
Tab键返回编辑模式，
going to click right here on this button
点击这里
to go to the vertex select and I will
进入顶点选择，按住
hold down the ALT key and then select
Alt键，选择这个顶点
that Loop of vertices there and I will
循环，稍微放大一点，
scale it up a bit and I can also bring
也可以缩小一点。
it back a bit and then maybe press the a
然后按A
key to select the entire mesh and scale
键选择整个网格，
everything in just a little bit let's
稍微放大一点。
also click on this button here to go to
点击这里进入
the face select we can select this face
面选择，选择这个面，稍微放大
and maybe bring it out a bit and scale
一点，再
it down a little bit so this is going to
缩小一点。这是
be the front of the fish and this will
鱼的正面，这是鱼的
be the back of the fish so we'll select
背面，我们选择
the back of the fish here and we will
鱼的背面，按
hit the I key to inser that face and
I键插入这个面。
then we can also scale it up on the
然后我们可以沿
z-axis and then also scale it and we'll
Z轴放大，再沿X轴缩小，最后按
hit X and scale it down on the X AIS and
X键
extrude out a little bit and then we'll
挤出。 先稍微拉伸一下，然后挤出，
extrude it out and then scale it up on
再沿
the z-axis so hit s and then Z we can
Z 轴放大，按 S 键，再按 Z 键，就可以
scale it up up and then extrude out
放大，然后再挤出，
again just like that let's now hit tab
就像这样。现在按 Tab 键
to go back to object mode that's going
回到物体模式，这将
to be the base of the fish so we'll now
是鱼的底部，接下来我们要
model the fins so in object mode I'm
建模鱼鳍。在物体模式下，我要
going to add a new object so press shift
添加一个新物体，按 Shift +
a for the add menu let's click here to
A 打开添加菜单，点击这里
add a cube and I'll hit tab to go into
添加一个立方体，然后按 Tab 键进入
edit mode and I can hit G to grab and
编辑模式，按 G 键抓取并沿 X
bring the cube over on the xaxis and
轴移动立方体，按
then hit s to scale and scale it down on
S 键缩放并沿
the z-axis and then scale the whole
Z 轴缩小，再稍微缩小一下。按
thing down a bit let's hit tab to go
Tab 键
back to object mode and I can move the
回到物体模式，我可以移动
cube over and bring it down and you can
立方体并缩小它。可以
see because I was editing it in object
看到，因为我是在物体
mode the origin point is still in the
模式下编辑的，所以原点仍然在
very center here so if I click here to
中心。点击这里进入
go to the modifiers let's click on ADD
修改器，点击“添加
modifier I can click here for the search
修改器”，点击这里进行搜索，
and I will search for Mirror We'll add
搜索“镜像”，添加
the mirror modifier so it's mirrored
镜像。 修改器会将其镜像
over to the other side because the
到另一侧，因为
mirror point is going to be from the
镜像点将来自
origin so I'll hit tab to go into edit
原点。所以我按 Tab 键进入编辑
mode and I can bring it in here into the
模式，然后可以把它拉到
fish maybe bring it down a little bit
鱼身上，稍微向下调整一下，再向上调整一下。
and bring it back a bit and then if I
然后
hold down the Z button and go into
按住 Z 键进入
wireframe view I will hit a to deselect
线框视图，按 A 键取消选择
everything I will click and drag just to
所有元素。点击并拖动
box select that part of the fin and I'll
鼠标框选鳍的这一部分，然后
scale it down on the Y AIS to make it
沿 Y 轴缩放，使其更尖锐。
pointy let's go back to solid View and I
回到实体视图，按 Ctrl+
will press controlr control R is going
R
to add a loop cut and I will left click
添加一个循环切割。左键单击，
and then right click so the loop cut
然后右键单击，使循环切割
stays where it is and then if I select
保持在原位。然后，选中这个顶点，
this vertex here and then hold down the
按住
shift key and select this vertex here I
Shift 键，再选中这个顶点，
can hit G to grab and bring it out on
按 G 键抓取并沿
the x axis and just make that fin longer
X 轴拉出，使鳍变长。
maybe select everything with the a ke
也许可以用 A 键选中所有元素，然后
and scale everything up on the Y AIS
沿 Y 轴缩放。
then I can rotate it let's rotate it
接下来可以旋转它，我们来旋转一下。
around you can also double tap the r key
你也可以双击 R 键
and that will enable the track ball
启用轨迹球
rotation and you can kind of rotate that
旋转。 可以把它
down and bring it down a little bit
向下旋转一点，再稍微降低一点，大概
something like that let's hit tab to go
这样。我们按 Tab 键
back to object node and I'll press
返回对象节点，然后按
control 2 to add a subdivision surface
Ctrl+2 添加一个两级细分曲面。
with two levels and then we can hit tab
接着按 Tab 键
to go back into edit mode and I will
返回编辑模式，按 Ctrl
press controlr to add a loop cut I will
添加一个循环切割。
left click and then drag this down over
左键单击，然后把它拖到
here and then left click again right
这里，再左键单击这里。按
there hit tab to go back to object mode
Tab 键返回对象模式，
and I will use the object context menu
使用对象上下文菜单，
and then choose shade smooth I use the
然后选择“平滑着色”。我用的是
right click select and blender so I hit
右键选择，也就是按
the W key but you can just right click
W 键，但你也可以直接右键
and then click on shade smooth let's
单击“平滑着色”。
also now add like a fin on the top so I
现在我们再在顶部添加一个鳍片。
will press shift C to make sure the 3D
按 Shift+C 确保 3D
cursor is in the very center there I
光标位于正中心。然后
will go to the add menu and we'll add a
打开添加菜单，添加一个
cube I'll press control 2 to add a
立方体。按 Ctrl+2 添加一个
subdivision surface with two levels and
两级细分曲面。把
we'll bring the cube up and then I will
立方体拉上来，然后
use the object context menu and shade it
使用对象上下文菜单选择“
smooth then we'll go into edit mode and
平滑着色”。进入编辑模式，
I'm going to scale it down on the X AIS
我把它沿 X 轴缩小，
and and then also scale it down the
然后再缩放一下。 沿着
z-axis and go back to object mode and
Z 轴向下移动，然后返回物体模式，把
move it over and bring it down here and
它移到这里，
then I can select these two vertices and
然后我可以选择这两个顶点，稍微向后
bring it back a bit something like that
移动一点，类似这样。选择
select these two vertices and bring them
这两个顶点，
back a little bit select everything and
稍微向后移动一点，选中所有顶点，
maybe scale it down on the z-axis or on
然后沿着 Z 轴或
the x axis like that and then I can
X 轴缩小它，像这样。然后我可以
press controlr for a loop cut and I can
按 Ctrl 键进行循环切割，我可以把
drag this down just to sharpen it and
它向下拖动来锐化它，然后
maybe scale everything down on the
沿着
z-axis like that all right go back to
Z 轴缩小所有顶点，像这样。好了，返回
object mode and that's looking pretty
物体模式，看起来很
good so so that's going to be the basic
不错。这就是
base mesh that we're going to use to
我们要用来雕刻的基本网格，
sculpt but I need to join this all
但我需要把它们连接起来，
together so that it's one object so
使之成为一个整体。在
before I join an object together I need
连接物体之前，我需要
to make sure that all the modifiers are
确保所有修改器都
the same or all the modifiers are
相同或所有修改器都已
applied so what I'm going to do is click
应用。所以我要点击
on the fins here and if I open the side
这里的鳍片，如果我打开侧面
panel you can see there is this mirror
板，你会看到这个镜像
modifier so let's click on the drop-
修改器。所以我们点击
down arrow right here and click on apply
这里的下拉箭头，然后点击应用。
so if I go into edit mode you can see
如果我进入编辑模式…… 现在你可以看到
it's actual geometry now so now you can
它的实际几何形状了，可以
see that each one of these objects have
看到每个物体都具有
the same subdivision surface model
相同的细分曲面模型。
so I'll select the fin hold down the
我先选中鳍，按住
shift key select the other Fin and then
Shift键，选中另一个鳍，然后
hold down the shift key and select the
按住Shift键，
body last and I will press contrl J and
最后选中鱼身，按下Ctrl+J，
that's going to join it together into
将它们合并成
one object now I want to make this much
一个物体。现在我想让它
more detailed so here on the levels
更精细一些，所以在“级别”、“
viewport and render I'm going to click
视口”和“渲染”中，我点击
here to turn these up so it's very very
这里来提高平滑度，把
smooth and I'm going to turn them up to
它调到5左右，这样就非常平滑了。
then if I click on the drop down I can
然后，如果我点击下拉菜单，可以
click on apply to apply the modifier so
点击“应用”来应用修改器。
if I hit tab to go into edit mode you
如果我按Tab键进入编辑模式，
can see the fish now is pretty Det
可以看到鱼现在非常精细了。
so we can now go into sculpt mode before
现在我们可以进入雕刻模式了，
we do that though let's save the project
不过在此之前，我们先保存项目。
so I'll click on file and click on Save
我点击“文件”，然后点击“保存”，把
and I'll just rename this to fish sculpt
它重命名为“鱼雕刻”，
and then click on Save blender file and
然后点击“保存Blender文件”，把
just save that on my computer so now we
它保存到我的电脑上。现在我们
can click right here to go to blender
可以点击这里打开Blender了。 进入
sculpt mode and it's going to take us
雕刻模式，这里会进入
into the sculpting mode here and then
雕刻模式。
brushes now before we start sculpting
现在，所有工具和笔刷都在这里。在开始雕刻之前，
this if I zoom in here and I go inside
如果我放大这里，进入
the sculpt you can see that there is
雕刻界面，可以看到
mesh which is overlapping we definitely
网格重叠了。我们绝对
don't want this because if I start to
不希望这样，因为如果我在
sculpt here you can see there's going to
这里开始雕刻，可以看到网格重叠会
be some really weird issues where the
出现一些非常奇怪的问题，
mesh is overlapping because there are
因为这里有
two different meshes so what I'm going
两个不同的网格。所以我要
to do is use blender's remesh feature to
使用Blender的重新网格化功能，将它们重新网格
actually remesh this all together so
化，使它们
connect and it won't be two different
连接在一起，而不是分成两个独立的
pieces of the object so again to use the
部分。再次强调，要使用
remesh you can press the r key and then
重新网格化功能，可以按R键，然后将
you can drag your mouse here and then
鼠标拖动到这里，
just click when it is pretty high
点击。选择较高的
quality so I'm going to make it about
质量（我这里设置的是高质量），
that high high quality and then you can
然后按Ctrl键，即可
remesh it so now you can see if I zoom
重新网格化。现在，如果我
in here you can see it's connecting if I
放大这里，可以看到它们连接在一起了。如果我
go into edit mode you can see the mesh
进入编辑模式…… 你可以看到网格
is connecting and also if I go inside
连接在一起了，而且如果我进入内部，
here you can see there isn't any
你可以看到没有任何
overlapping faces or any objects which
重叠的面或任何
are separate so it's all just one object
分离的对象，所以它就是一个整体。
so now we can start to sculpt this now
现在我们可以开始雕刻了。
as I talked about earlier we want to
正如我之前提到的，我们要
turn on the symmetry so it mirrors our
启用对称功能，这样它就能将
sculp thing from one side over to the
雕刻的内容从一侧镜像到
other side so we're going to click on
另一侧。所以我们要点击
this x right here so now you can see
这里的“x”。现在你可以看到
there's that little blue dot there so if
这里有个小蓝点。如果
I sculpt on this side it's it's going to
我在这一侧雕刻，它就会
mirror it over to the other side but
镜像到另一侧。不过，
I'll press contrl Z to undo that now
我会按 Ctrl+Z 来撤销这个操作。在
before I sculpt this there is another
雕刻之前，
setting that I want to turn on if I
我还要启用另一个设置。如果我
click here on the brush and click on
点击画笔，然后点击
this drop down there's going to be a
这个下拉菜单，你会看到
bunch of different brush settings what I
很多不同的画笔设置。
bottom and I'm going to turn on this
我要一直向下滚动，然后启用“
front faces only so I'll check mark that
仅正面”选项。我会勾选它。
if this is turned off let me just show
如果这个选项关闭，让我给
you what can happen so if this is turned
你演示一下会发生什么。如果这个选项
off and I'm like sculpting here you can
关闭，我就像…… 在这里雕刻时，你可以
see that it might start to sculpt on the
看到它可能会开始雕刻
other side and it won't sculpt just from
另一侧，而不仅仅是从
the front faces and you can see just
正面雕刻。你可以看到刚才就
happened right here you can see I was
发生了这种情况。我当时正在
sculpting right here but as I was
这里雕刻，但当我在
sculpting right here these faces were
这里雕刻时，这些面靠
really close because this is a pretty
得很近，因为这是
thin part of the mesh it's pretty thin
网格中非常薄的部分，
here so these faces started to be pulled
这里很薄，所以这些面开始
along with my sculpting and so it messed
随着我的雕刻动作被拉扯，从而破坏了
up the mesh so let me just press contrl
网格。所以让我按 Ctrl+
Z to undo that so if I click on the
Z 撤销一下。如果我点击
brush drop down and then choose front
笔刷下拉菜单，然后选择“
faces only it's going to only sculpt the
仅雕刻正面”，它就只会雕刻面的正面。
front of the faces and this in here
这里，
inside the mesh that's the back of the
网格内部是
face but out here that's the front of
面的背面，而这里是
the face so now if I start to sculpt
面的正面。所以现在，如果我从这里开始雕刻，
here if I sculpt along here now you can
如果我沿着这里雕刻，你可以
see we're not having that issue even if
看到我们没有遇到这个问题。即使
I sculpt on this part which is like
我雕刻这部分非常
really close you can see it's only going
接近的部分，你可以看到它也只会
to sculpt on the front faces if I sculpt
雕刻面。
like this it's kind of grabbing both of
像这样雕刻的话，它会同时抓住两个
the faces so that is kind of messing it
面，所以有点搞砸了，
up so I'll press contrl Z to undo that
所以我按 Ctrl+Z 撤销一下。
but if I just sculpt right here on this
但如果我只雕刻鳍片的
front part here of the fin you can see
正面，你可以看到
it's not affecting the back of the mesh
它不会影响网格的背面。
but I'm going to press contrl Z just to
不过我还是要按 Ctrl+Z
undo all that sculpting because that was
撤销一下雕刻，因为这只是个
just an example now something to be
例子。现在需要
aware of is that if I click here onto a
注意的是，如果我点击这里切换到
different brush set
另一个笔刷组，
and then click on the brush here then
然后再点击这个笔刷，
you can see I might need to turn on the
你可以看到我可能需要
front faces only again so if you're
再次启用“仅正面”选项。所以如果你
having issues with that if you're
遇到这个问题，比如
sculpting and you realize that it kind
你在雕刻时发现它
of pulled some of the back of the mesh
拉扯到了网格的背面，
then just make sure that this brush
那么请确保这个笔刷的“
front faces only is turned on because if
仅正面”选项已启用，因为如果
you switch to a different brush it might
你切换到其他笔刷，它可能会被
be turned off so let's start by using
关闭。那么我们先用
the grab brush to add some details to
抓取笔刷给鳍片添加一些细节。
the fins so you can hit the g key or you
你可以按 G 键，或者
can click here to go to the grab brush
点击这里切换到抓取笔刷。
and for the grab brush I really don't
对于抓取笔刷，我其实不需要……
need the front faces only to be on
只显示正面
that's not important because I'm pulling
并不重要，因为我是在
around on the mesh so I don't need to
网格上拖动，所以不用
worry about that and then again you can
担心正面。你可以在这里
change the strength right here and the
调整强度和
radius I'm going to make the radius
半径。我要缩小半径，你可以拖动
smaller by either draging here or you
这里，或者
can press the F key and then drag over
按 F 键，然后拖动并点击
and then click there to make it a bit
这里来缩小半径。
smaller so let's now use the grab brush
现在我们用抓取笔刷
to pull out some cool details so right
来提取一些细节。在这个
here on this fin I'm going to click and
鳍片上，我点击并
drag to kind of pull this out a bit and
拖动来稍微拉出一点。然后在
then right here I can kind of push this
这里，我可以把它推回去。再在这里，我可以把它推回去。最后，在
push this in and then here at the end I
末端，我
can kind of push that out a bit and also
可以把它拉出来一点。点击这里，然后用
pen on my tablet to kind of push that
数位板笔的“Along”键点击，把它拉出来。
out let's also do the same thing on the
我们在背面也做同样的操作。
back here so if I go to the back I can
如果我切换到背面，我可以把
kind of pull this out here maybe zoom
它拉出来，也许可以
out a bit pull this out then zoom in a
稍微缩小一下，把它拉出来，然后再放大
little bit and kind of pull it out even
一点，把它拉出来
more to kind of sharpen it up and then
更多，让它更清晰。然后在
right here I can kind of tap here just
这里，我可以
lightly and kind of push that in a
轻轻点击一下，然后…… 稍微往里推一点，
little bit and then back here or kind of
然后回到这里，或者说在
on the end I can zoom in and tap along
末端，我可以放大，然后沿着
here just to pull out that area like
这里点击，就能把那部分区域拉出来。
that and then right up here I can kind
然后，在这里我可以轻轻
of tap along here to kind of pull that
点击，把它拉出来。
out there so now you can see already we
现在你可以看到，
have some really cool details to our
我们的鱼已经有一些很酷的细节了。在
fish and as you're sculpting you can
雕刻过程中，你可以
press crl s to save the file or you can
按 Ctrl+S 保存文件，或者
click on file and just click on save to
点击“文件”，然后点击“保存”来
save your project and of course you can
保存你的项目。当然，你可以
see right over here it's done it for the
看到，
other side because we have the Symmetry
另一侧也已经完成了，因为我们启用了对称功能。
on so now let's do the same thing for
现在，让我们对
the fin here the Top Fin so I'll just
这里的鳍，也就是顶鳍，做同样的操作。我轻轻
kind of tap along here to kind of pull
点击这里，把这
out this area and then I can click and
部分拉出来，然后在
drag or tap along there on my tablet to
我的平板电脑上点击并拖动或点击，把它
kind of push that in then I can pop this
推进去。然后我可以把它拉出来一点，再把
out here then I can push this in a bit
它推进去一点，
and then I can kind of pull this part
然后我可以把这部分拉出来一点，
out here maybe I can even pull this back
也许我还可以把它往后拉
a bit so it's a bit more round maybe
一点，让它更圆润一些，甚至可以
even bring this down a little bit all
把它往下移一点。好的，
right and then maybe here kind of push
然后也许可以把这里往外推一点，让它
this out so it's a little bit bigger up
更大一些，
here maybe pull this part out here and
也许可以把这部分拉出来，再把这部分
push this in there so there we go you
推进去一点。好了，你
can already see it's looking more like a
可以看到它看起来更像了。 这是一个
stylized fish you can also kind of pull
风格化的鱼，你可以
around this part here if you want to
拖动这部分来
kind of change the front or the face of
改变鱼的正面或脸部，甚至可以把
of pull this out just to make it a bit
它拉出来，让它
more smooth and round and you can just
更流畅圆润一些。
change the proportions now is a good
现在正是调整比例的好
time to change the proportions before we
时机，在我们
add more details and if this is looking
添加更多细节之前，调整一下比例。如果看起来
a little bit stretched we might as well
有点拉伸，我们可以重新划分网格。
remesh it so press the r key and that's
按 R 键，这
going to bring up the remesh setting I
将打开重新划分网格的设置。我
can't see it so I need to zoom out press
看不到它，所以我需要缩小视图。按
the r key and I can drag this around and
R 键，我可以拖动它。
I want this to be pretty detailed so
我希望它非常精细，所以
maybe like click right there and then
点击这里，然后按 Ctrl 键，这将重新划分网格。
remesh it so now if I hold down the Z
现在，如果我按住 Z
button and move my mouse over to the
键，将鼠标移动到
wireframe and then let go you can now
线框上，然后松开，你可以
kind of see how detailed that is and it
看到它的细节程度，它
fixed any geometry that we kind of
修复了我们拖动过的任何几何体。
pulled around now let's also hold down
现在，我们按住 Shift
the shift key and remember the holding
键，记住按住 Shift
down the shift key is going to go to the
键会切换到
smooth brush or you can also just click
平滑笔刷，或者你也可以
on the smooth Brush by clicking right
通过单击鼠标右键来选择平滑笔刷。
here but I'm just going to hold down the
这里，我按住
shift key and then I can just lightly
Shift键，然后轻轻地把
smooth this out here lightly smooth this
这里抹平，轻轻地把周围抹平，让
out where the fins are connecting to the
鳍和
body maybe hold down the shift key and
身体连接的地方更平滑一些。按住Shift键，轻轻地把这里和那里抹平。
all right and then also we can go right
好的，然后我们也可以到
up here and lightly hold down the the
这里，轻轻地按住
shift key and just press down very
Shift键，轻轻地向下按压，把这里抹平。
there and smooth that out there so now
现在我们来
let's sculpt in the eye sockets and for
雕刻眼窝。
sculpting in the eye sockets I like to
雕刻眼窝时，我喜欢
use the clay strips brush and I'll press
用黏土条笔刷，我会按
the F key to make my brush a bit smaller
F键把笔刷缩小一点，然后放大这里。接下来，
sculpting I'm going to hold down the
我不会像雕刻那样把黏土推出来，而是按住
control key and then sculpt and that's
Ctrl键，然后选择雕刻，这样就会把
going to push in the clay and I'm just
黏土推进去。我在
going to go around in circles here and
这里画圈，把
just kind of push in where the eyes are
眼睛周围的地方推进去。这样就差不多了，
so that's what pretty good I like how
我很喜欢这种效果。
bigger if you want to so just going
如果你觉得可以，可以把它做得更大一些。 所以我就绕着
around here in circles and kind of
这里画圈，在
pushing in where the eye sockets are and
眼窝那里轻轻按压，
then let's also press crlr just to
然后按 Ctrl 键重新网格
remesh it again so it adds a bit more
化一下，这样可以给
detail to that area go along there and
那个区域增加一些细节。沿着那里走，
then hold down the shift key and you can
然后按住 Shift 键，就可以
just lightly smooth that out where
轻轻地把雕刻好的地方平滑一下。好了，这样就
pretty good if you want to hit the g key
很好了。如果你想用
for the grab brush you can also kind of
抓取笔刷，可以按 G 键，还可以
play around with the shape of it if you
调整它的形状，比如
want to like make it a little bit bigger
让它更大一些，或者
or kind of pull the eyes closer together
把眼睛拉近一些之类的。现在
looking pretty good so we're going to
看起来很不错了。
add a different object in here which is
接下来我们要添加一个不同的物体，一个
going to be kind of a cartoony eye you
卡通风格的眼睛。你
can also while you're still using the
也可以在使用
grab brush you can kind of pull this
抓取笔刷的时候，把它拉
down and maybe shape the fish a little
下来，稍微调整一下鱼的
bit kind of shape the front of the fish
形状，比如鱼的前端。
if you want to so now I want to carve in
现在我要雕刻
the mouth and to carve away the mouth I
嘴巴，要雕刻嘴巴的部分，我
can use the crease brush so I'm going to
可以使用褶皱笔刷。所以我点击
click right here to go to the crease
这里切换到褶皱笔刷。
brush I'll press the F key to make my
按 F 键
brush smaller and I can just find a spot
缩小笔刷，然后在这里找个位置，沿着这里开始画褶皱。我们
click and drag here to make the strength
点击并拖动这里，稍微增强一下
of it a little bit bigger and then I can
笔触力度，然后沿着这里开始画
where that mouth is all right so
嘴巴周围的褶皱。像
something like that crease that in there
这样画褶皱，按住
maybe hold down the shift key and kind
Shift 键，稍微
of smooth out the bottom lip there all
柔化一下下唇。这样好多了，画出褶皱，
crease that in there and then just
然后沿着这里画，
crease along there try to keep it kind
尽量保持
of smooth and then hold down the shift
柔和。按住 Shift 键，可以稍微柔化一下。可以稍微缩小一下，让它更柔和一些。
then also let's crease down here all
然后我们再画一下这里的褶皱。好的，让它向上延伸，然后再向下延伸。
down you can also press crlr again and
你也可以再次按下 Ctrl 键，重新调整网格，增加
that'll kind of remesh it so it has a
一些
bit more detail and then you can hit the
细节。然后按
g key for the grab brush and you can
G 键使用抓取笔刷，可以
kind of pull this around if you want to
拖动它来
change the shape of it so maybe I'll
改变形状。比如，我把它向下
like push this down a little bit and
推。 稍微调整一下，把
kind of pull up the nose a little bit
鼻子稍微向上提一点，
just there's kind of a subtle bump there
那里有个小小的凸起。
and then you can kind of change the
然后你可以改变
smile or change the shape of the mouth
笑容或者嘴型，比如
so something like that I want him to
我想让他
maybe be smiling a little bit more so I
笑得更灿烂一些，所以我可以把
can kind of pull up that mouth there and
嘴巴向上提一下。
right here I actually want to pull in
这里，我其实想把
the mouth so I'll just use the grab
嘴巴往里拉一点，所以我用抓取
brush and kind of just pull in that
笔刷，把鼠标拉进去一点，让它更
Mouse so it's a little bit more thin now
细一些。接下来，
what I'm also going to do is click here
我还要点击这里切换
to go to the clay strips brush and then
到黏土条笔刷，然后沿着这里
I can go along here and just lightly add
轻轻地添加一些
a little bit more clay and then hold
黏土，
down the shift key and lightly smooth
按住Shift键轻轻地把它抹平。我们
that out there let's go back here to the
回到这里，切换到
crease brush and then I can just crease
褶皱笔刷，然后我可以稍微压出一些褶皱。
this in just a little bit now I want to
现在我想对
do some more detailed sculpting for the
鳃和鳞片进行一些更细致的雕刻，
gills and the scales so what I'm going
所以我
now and I'm going to use the DPO feature
现在要停止使用重新网格功能，我要使用DPO功能，
so this will add geometry as I sculpt
这样在我雕刻的时候就会添加几何体。
and if I'm sculpting in a more detailed
如果我…… 在更精细的
area it'll add more geometry so I'm
区域进行雕刻会增加更多几何形状，所以我要
going to click on this check mark here
点击这里的勾号，
and then just just click on okay let's
然后点击确定。我们再按一次 Ctrl+
also press crl s to save this file again
S 保存文件。
so now the DPO is turned on and I'm
现在 DPO 已开启，我
going to click right here to go to the
点击这里切换到
clay strips brush and if I click right
粘土条笔刷。如果我点击
here on the DPO settings the detail size
DPO 设置中的这里，细节大小
is 10 let me just sculpt along here and
是 10。我在这里雕刻一下
see how that is I think I'll press
看看效果。我想我应该按
contrl Z to undo that let's turn the D
Ctrl+Z 撤销一下。我们把 D
Topo down even smaller to maybe just
拓扑调得更小一些，比如
like a f five so now I'll press the F
F5。现在我按 F
key to make my brush a bit smaller and
键缩小笔刷。
I'm going to start by sculpting kind of
我要先雕刻一个
little Gill so I will go along here and
小鳃，所以我沿着这里
just add a bit of clay and kind of
添加一些粘土，
sculpt in like a gill there all right
雕刻出一个鳃的形状。好的，
like that and then also right here just
就像这样。然后在这里也
sculpt it a little bit all right go
稍微雕刻一下。好的，
along there just add a bit of clay there
沿着这里添加一些粘土。
and then I will hold down the shift key
然后我按住 Shift 键。
and holding down the shift key is going
按住 Shift 键会……
to go to the smooth brush and I can just
切换到平滑笔刷，我可以把
smooth that out there but I'm going to
这里平滑一下，但我先
leave this part here cuz that's going to
保留这部分，因为这里
be the Gill and then if I want to crease
是鳃。如果我想让
this a bit I can go to the crease brush
它有点褶皱，可以切换到褶皱笔刷，
and I can just go along here and just
沿着这里轻轻地
crease it in just a little bit maybe
压出一点褶皱，可以
turn down the strength so it's not quite
调低一下力度，让它不
as strong and just crease that in a
那么强烈。
little bit now remember if you hold down
记住，按住Ctrl
the control key it's going to do the
键会产生
opposite effect so if I want to pinch
相反的效果。所以如果我想把
this out and kind of sharpen it I can
这里收紧一些，让它更锐利，可以
hold down the control key with the
按住Ctrl键，用
crease brush and just kind of pinch that
褶皱笔刷轻轻地收紧，这样就能把它拉出来
out and kind of pinch it a little bit
一点。
now you can see we have that little
现在你可以看到这里有一条小小的
Ridge there and then if you don't hold
脊状突起。如果你不
down the control key and just sculpt
按住Ctrl键，直接用雕刻笔刷，它就会把这条脊状突起收紧。好了，我们现在就画了
so there we go we have kind of a little
一个
simple Gill and now I'm going to go
简单的鳃。接下来我要沿着
along here and I'm going to sculpt some
这里雕刻一些
scales so I'll go back here to the clay
鳞片。 我回到这里的粘土
strips brush and I'm just going to go
条画笔，
along here and kind of make these little
沿着这里画一些类似
like backwards C shapes or kind of like
反C形或
half moon shapes and then go along here
半月形的小图案，然后沿着这里
to fill it and then hold down the shift
填充，按住Shift键平滑一下。好的，我们再来这里重复一遍。沿着这里画一个半月形，然后按住Shift
key and kind of smooth that all right
键平滑一下。
key and smooth that out there go along
沿着这里再画一个，按住Shift键
the shift key smooth that out there we
平滑一下。我们
can just start to make a cool pattern
可以开始画
there for some stylized scales and then
一些风格化的鳞片图案了。然后我们再添加一些鳞片。
let's add some more scales so this time
这次
I'm going to start the scales on the
我要从
center of the other one so we can add
另一个鳞片的中心开始画，这样我们就可以添加
another layer of scales and this one is
另一层鳞片了。这一层鳞片要
going to go up there and then end on the
画到上面，然后结束在
other top of that layer of scales so go
另一层鳞片的顶部。
along there you can also smooth this out
沿着这里画，
if you kind of added too much detail
如果你觉得细节太多，也可以平滑一下。
there all right and then kind of fill
好的，然后填充一下，
holding down the shift key all right and
按住Shift键平滑一下。好的，
then this one here we can start it right
接下来这一层，我们可以从
here and it can come up and then go back
这里开始画。 可以先向上移动，然后再向下移动，
down bring that out more and then hold
让它更突出一些，然后
down the shift key and kind of smooth
按住Shift键，
that out a bit more like that all right
稍微平滑一下，就像这样。好的，
so now we have some more scales let's
现在我们有一些鳞片了，我们
also add maybe another like half one
再加半片，然后
there and then just hold down the shift
按住Shift
key and smooth that out there and then
键，把它平滑一下。然后
we'll add another half one kind of right
我们再加半片，就在这儿，算是
there which is kind of ending all right
结尾。好的，
add more clay and then hold down the
再加一些黏土，然后按住
shift key and smooth that out there and
Shift键，把它平滑一下。
then we'll add another one here so go up
然后我们再加一个，上下移动，就在
and down all right around there hold
这儿，
down the shift key and smooth that out
按住Shift键，把它平滑一下。
and then right up here we'll add another
然后我们再加一个，
ones this one will go up and then kind
这个向上移动，然后就到这儿了，
of end right over there and then hold
然后
down the shift key and smooth that one
按住Shift键，把它也平滑一下。
out as well you can also hit the g key
你也可以按G键打开
for the grab brush and then you can kind
抓取笔刷，然后你可以
of pull this around if you want them to
拖动它，如果你想让它们更突出一些，
like pop out a bit more or if you just
或者只是
want to kind of play around with the
想调整一下
shape of them all right that's pretty
它们的形状。好的，很不错。
is you can go to the crease brush so
你还可以使用褶皱
back to the crease brush if you want to
笔刷，所以如果你想……
you can hold down the control key and
你可以按住Ctrl键，然后捏出
edges of the scales so they're a bit
鳞片的边缘，让它们更
more visible so I'm just going to keep
清晰可见。我会继续这样
on doing that and add a bit more scales
做，给鱼的其他部分添加更多鳞片，
to the rest of the fish and holding down
按住
the shift key smoothing that part out
Shift键来平滑这些部分。
there we can go along here add another
我们可以继续添加，
one and if you'd rather what you could
如果你不想
do without smoothing them out is you
平滑
could first just sculpt all of them so
它们，可以先雕刻所有鳞片，比如
like sculpt that one there that one
雕刻这个、那个
there and that one there and then once
和那个，雕刻完成后再平滑它们。这样做可能更
that that might be a bit easier and then
容易一些。然后
we'll add another one kind of coming up
我们再添加一个，从这里向上延伸，再在这里添加一个，再在这里添加一个，
here then we'll add another one right
然后在
the bottom of the fish just going around
鱼的底部再添加一个，绕着鱼的底部
kind of in circles while holding down
画圈，同时按住
the shift key to smooth that out and
Shift键来平滑它们。
I'll just do a few more layers of these
我再添加几个。 好了，这些
scales all right and I'm going to call
鳞片已经一层层地画好了，
fish now another detail that I want to
鱼身上的鳞片部分就到此为止了。现在我想添加另一个细节，比如
the fins so I'll go to the crease brush
鱼鳍上的一些褶皱。所以我选择褶皱笔刷，
and we still have the D Topo on so it'll
我们仍然启用了D Topo，这样在
add more geometry as we sculpt and I'll
雕刻时可以增加更多几何形状。我
just go along here maybe actually make
沿着这里画，也许可以把笔刷的
my strength quite a bit bigger make the
力度调大一些，让它更
strength a bit stronger and I'll go
明显一些。然后我沿着
lines here just to add a bit more detail
这里画一些细线，增加一些细节。
I think that's pretty cool adding some
我觉得沿着鱼鳍添加一些线条很不错。
then we can go up here to the top and we
然后我们可以到鱼的顶部，
can do like the same thing so go along
做同样的事情。沿着
there and just add a bit of details to
那里画，给鱼鳍添加一些细节。这很棒。
that's kind of cool and then also let's
然后我们再到鱼尾，也就是尾部。
the tail and I can go along there maybe
我可以沿着那里画，也许可以在上面
add another one right up here and then
再加一条线，然后在下面再加
down here add another one and then we
一条。然后我们
can just kind of fill those all in by
可以通过
adding more of those lines so just adds
添加更多线条来填充这些区域，这样就增加了一些
a cool detail to that kind of cartoony
很酷的细节。 这种卡通
stylized fish and there we go that
风格的鱼，
really adds a lot to the fish and then
确实为鱼增添了不少色彩。接下来
another cool setting that I want to show
我想向你展示画笔设置里的另一个很棒的功能：
click here on stroke this will change
点击“描边”按钮，即可改变
the stroke of the brush and right now
画笔的描边。现在
it's set to space so this is basically
它设置为“间距”，所以基本上
going to add little kind of stamps of
会添加一些小点状的笔触。
the brush but the spacing is set to 10
但是间距设置为10，
so you're not really going to be able to
所以即使我把间距调大，你也看不出来。
spacing now if I click and drag you can
如果我把间距调得非常大，点击并拖动，你会
see there's going to be a big space
看到在出现小点之前会有一大块空白。
so what I can do is I can click right
所以我可以点击
here to go to the draw brush and then I
这里进入“绘制画笔”选项，然后把笔触
can make the strength a lot bigger then
强度调大一些。接着，
if I click here on the stroke settings
点击这个笔触设置，我们稍微
spacing up a little bit maybe to just
增加一下间距，比如调到
like 90 and now if I go along here you
90。现在，如果我沿着这个方向拖动，你
can see it's going to add some little
会看到它会添加一些小
dots there so that's pretty cool so
点，这很酷。
that's just another useful tool I'll
这只是另一个很有用的工具。我
press contrl zto to undo that so let me
按Ctrl+Z撤销操作。 好，我回到
go back to the stroke and let's turn it
笔触设置，把它调大一点，
up a little bit more maybe like 150 and
比如 150。
then if I kind of go along here you can
然后，我沿着这条线画，可以
see I can add some little dots so maybe
看到我可以添加一些小点。比如，我可以放大到
cheeks of the fish and then I can make
鱼的脸颊部分，然后把
my brush really small and I can just go
画笔调小，
along here and add some dots although
沿着这条线添加一些点。不过，现在的
that spacing is a little bit too close
间距有点太近了，
so again let me just Che take the stroke
所以我再调整一下笔触
spacing and turn that up to maybe like
间距，把它调大到
200 or 300 and then I can just go along
200 或 300。然后，我就可以沿着这条线画了。
here and you could also just click and
你也可以点击或
tap if you wanted to but this is a cool
轻触来添加细节，但这是一种
way to quickly add some more details so
快速添加细节的好方法。
that's kind of cool if you want to add
如果你想添加一些
like a bit of a pattern there or some
图案或者
details on the fish you could do that
鱼身上的一些细节，这很实用。在
and while we're on the stroke settings
笔触设置里，
you can also change the stroke method so
你还可以更改笔触方式。
on default it's set to space but another
默认设置为间距，但
cool one you could choose you could do
你也可以选择
like the line instead so let's change
线条。所以我们把它改成线条。
this to line and then back on the stroke
然后回到笔触
settings will turn the spacing way down
设置，把间距调小到
just to around the default which is
接近默认值，大约是
about 10 and so if I use the line if I
10，所以如果我使用线条，
click and drag here you can see it's
点击并拖动这里，你可以看到它会
going to show me a line and then when I
显示一条线，然后当我
let go it's going to sculpt the line
松开鼠标时，它会雕刻出这条线，这
there so that is pretty cool you could
很酷，你可以
add some cool details maybe it's not the
添加一些很酷的细节。也许它不太
best for this fish model I don't really
适合这个鱼模型，我不太清楚
know what I would add to it but if you
我会添加什么，但如果你
wanted to kind of create some lines you
想创建一些线条，你
could do that with the line stroke so
可以使用线条描边。
that's going to be it for the sculpt
雕刻部分就到此为止，
thing so I'm going to call this done for
我暂时就说到这里。接下来，
now so I am going to show you how you
我将向你展示如何
can do some cool painting and you can
进行一些很酷的绘画，你可以
actually paint some colors on this fish
在这条鱼身上涂上一些颜色。
but before I do that I want to model the
但在那之前，我想先建模
eyes so I'm going to click here to go
眼睛，所以我点击这里
back to the layout and I will press
返回布局，然后按 Ctrl+S
contrl s to save the project and I'm
保存项目。接下来我将
just going to use my mouse and keyboard
使用鼠标和键盘来
for this just to model the eye so I'm
建模眼睛，所以我
going to press shift C to make sure that
按 Shift+C 确保
3D cursor is in the very center of the
3D 光标位于
seam and I'll go to the add menu and I'm
接缝的正中心，然后进入添加菜单。
just going to add a UV sphere and I'll
添加一个UV球体，然后将
bring the UV sphere forward on the Y AIS
其沿Y轴向前移动，接着按
and then I can hit tab to go into edit
Tab键进入编辑
mode and I can scale it down and I can
模式，缩小它，并
move it here and just move it inside
移动到
where the fish's eye is and then let's
鱼眼的位置。然后
also click here and add modifier here in
点击这里，在修改器中添加一个修改器，搜索“镜像”，
for mirror and we'll add the mirror
添加镜像
modifier and then I can double tap the r
修改器。然后双击R
key and double tapping the r key will
键，双击R键会
use the track ball rotation and I'm just
使用轨迹球旋转，旋转一下，让
going to rotate this around so the fish
鱼看起来像这样
is kind of looking forward like that and
向前看。接着缩小它，把
just stick the eye there in the eye
眼睛放回眼窝里，现在有点太
sockets that's a bit too far out so
靠外了，稍微往后移一点。
and then I'll hit tab to go back to
然后按Tab键返回
object mode and I'll use the object
物体模式，使用物体
context menu and shade that smooth and
上下文菜单添加平滑着色。接着按
then also let's press control 2 control
Ctrl+2，Ctrl+
2 is the shortcut key for adding a
2是添加
subdivision surface modifier so it's
细分曲面修改器的快捷键，让表面
more smooth let's go back into edit mode
更平滑。现在回到编辑模式，可以
now maybe can scale this up a bit and
放大一下。 稍微调整一下，
then I want to add kind of a little bump
然后我想给
for like the iris or the pupo so I'm
虹膜或眼窝加点凸起，所以我
going to hold down the ALT key and then
按住 ALT 键，选中那个循环，然后按住
then I can hold down the shift and ALT
Shift 和 ALT
key and select that Loop right there and
键选中那个循环，再按住 Shift 键选中那个顶点，然后按 E 键进行扩展，再按 S 键缩放，把它缩小一点。
smaller and then what I can also do is
我还可以
add a loop cut to kind of sharpen this
添加一个循环切割来让它更锐利，
up so I'll press crlr to add a loop cut
所以我按 Ctrl+R 添加循环切割，
and I can click and drag over and then
点击并拖动，然后
just click to place that there so if I
点击放置。
go back to object mode now you can see
现在回到物体模式，可以看到
we have a cute ey there for our fish
我们给鱼做了一个可爱的眼睛，我们
let's press contrl s to save this and
按 Ctrl+S 保存，
then we can hold down the Z button and
然后按住 Z 键
we can go down into the material preview
进入材质预览，
just to see what the materials look like
看看材质的效果，
and we can create a material for the eye
我们可以为眼睛创建一个材质，
so we'll select the eye let's click here
所以我们选中眼睛，点击
on the material let's click on new to
材质，然后点击新建
add a new material and I can just call
添加一个新材质。 我可以把
this white and then here on the
它命名为白色，然后在这里，
roughness we'll turn that to zero so
我们将粗糙度设置为零，这样
it's really shiny and on the base color
它就会非常闪亮。在基础颜色中，
I'll make this fully white now I just
我将其设置为纯白色。现在，我
want to add a dark area where the center
想在眼睛中心添加一个暗区，
of the eye is so I will hit the Tab Key
所以我按 Tab 键
to go into edit mode I'm going to hit a
进入编辑模式。按 A 键取消
to deselect everything I will hold down
选择所有对象。按住
the ALT key and select that Loop there
Alt 键选择循环，
and then hold down the shift and ALT key
然后按住 Shift 和 Alt 键再次选择循环，再按住
shift and ALT key and select that Loop
Shift 和 Alt 键选择循环。
and then if you just hold down the shift
按住 Shift
key you can select the center vertex so
键可以选择中心顶点。
we'll now click on the plus here to add
现在，我们点击这里的加号添加
a new material let's click on new and I
新材质。点击“新建”，我
can click on this to rename it and I'll
可以点击这里重命名，我将
rename this to Black and then we can
其重命名为“黑色”。然后
click on the assign button and that will
点击“分配”按钮，将
assign that black material to just those
黑色材质分配给这些
faces so I will hit tab to go back to
面。按 Tab 键返回
object node and then if I click on the
对象节点。如果我点击
base color on the black material will
黑色材质的基础颜色，它会
make it fully black and I can take the
变成纯黑色。我可以把
roughness and turn it all the way down
粗糙度调到最低，
so it is shiny so now we have some cute
这样它就会很闪亮。现在我们有了…… 画上一些可爱的
cartoony eyes so now we can do some
卡通眼睛，现在我们可以给
painting here on on the fish so I'm
鱼上色了。我要
going to go back to blender sculpt mode
回到Blender的雕刻模式，
and blender sculpt mode actually has a
Blender的雕刻模式其实也有一个
painting mode now it's not exactly the
绘画模式。它和
same as texture painting where you're
纹理绘制不太一样，纹理绘制是在
texture painting on a texture and then
纹理上绘制，然后再将
you're UV unwrapping the texture onto
纹理UV展开到
the object this mode for texture
物体上。而这个纹理
painting actually uses the vertices or
绘制模式实际上是利用顶点或
the detail of the mesh to paint the
网格的细节来绘制
different colors so I'm going to scroll
不同的颜色。所以我把
my mouse down here and you can see that
鼠标滚轮向下滚动，可以看到
there's a paint mode so I'm going to
这里有一个绘画模式。我
click on the paint mode and then for the
点击绘画模式，然后
painting I'm going to bring back my
调出我的
drawing towel
绘图工具。
so if you're in the paint mode you can
在绘画模式下，你可以
see right up here there is this black
看到这里有一个黑色的，还有一个
one and then this white one here but the
白色的。
black one is the main color so if I
黑色是主色，所以我
click on this color I can make it
点击这个颜色，就可以
whatever I color I want with the color
用色轮把它调成我想要的任何颜色。
wheel so I'm going to make it like a red
我把它调成红色。
for the brush so you can see there's the
画笔的设置也一样，你可以看到
brush strength and the radius I'll press
画笔强度和半径。我按下
the F key to make the radius bigger and
F键。 关键是要把半径调大，
then I can start to go along here and I
然后我就可以开始沿着这条线
can paint now as I mentioned earlier
绘制了。正如我之前提到的，
this isn't actually a texture map this
这实际上并不是纹理贴图，
is just using the detail of the geometry
而是利用几何体的细节
to paint this so if you're trying to
来绘制。所以，如果你尝试
paint this using a very low poly model
用一个非常低多边形的模型来绘制，
then it's not going to work correctly
那效果不会很好，细节也不会
and it's not going to be very detailed
很丰富。
but because this object is really detail
但是因为这个物体细节非常丰富，
and it has lots of geometry we're
有很多几何体，所以可以正常绘制。 我们
actually painting on the vertices and
实际上是在顶点上作画，
each Vertex or each face is going to be
每个顶点或每个面都会有
a different color so it works well for
不同的颜色，所以这种方法很适合
just quickly doing some basic coloring
快速地给模型上一些基本颜色。
to the model so now that I've painted
现在我已经用
this in all with the red I'm going to
红色涂满了，我要
click here on the color wheel and I'm
点击色轮上的这个位置，把它
going to change this to a bright yellow
改成亮黄色。
color and then I can also click here to
然后我还可以点击这里
make my brush stronger and I can zoom in
增强笔刷，放大画面，然后沿着这里画，用
paint this and I can paint it in yellow
黄色涂。
and again here we have the Symmetry
这里我们开启了对称功能（点击
turned on with the X there so it's going
X），所以它会
to be mirrored over to the other side so
镜像到另一侧。
I can just go along here and I can just
我可以沿着这里
paint along here paint in yellow that's
画，用黄色涂，效果
pretty cool and then let's click on the
很棒。然后我们
color again and this time I'm going to
再点击颜色，这次我要把
change it to like an orangey color and
它改成橙色，
I'll make my brush less strong and I
降低笔刷强度，
will go along here and just paint a
沿着这里画一点橙色，
little bit of an orange color maybe make
也许让橙色更
towards the yellow and just paint a
偏向黄色一些，
little bit of orange here a along where
沿着鳞片画一点橙色，
the scales are and also maybe along here
也许…… 这里
paint that a bit of orange and down here
涂一点橙色，下面这里也
make that a little bit orange and also
涂一点橙色，还有
the belly of the fish I thought that'd
鱼的肚子，我觉得
be fun to make it a bit orange all right
涂成橙色会很有趣，就这样。
something like that and then maybe on
然后在鱼背上，
of orange here along the back fin so
沿着背鳍也可以涂一点橙色，这样看起来
something like that is pretty cool so I
很酷。
will now click on the layout to go back
现在我点击布局，回到
to the layout view now you can see in
布局视图。在布局视图中，你可以看到，按住 Z 键进入
and go to the material preview or click
材质预览，或者点击
on this button to go into the material
这个按钮进入材质预览，或者按住
preview or if you hold the Z button and
Z 键
go into the rendered view to see what
进入渲染视图，看看渲染后的实际效果。
rendered you can see that it's not
你会发现它
actually showing the colors and that's
实际上并没有显示颜色，这是
because we need to do a very simple
因为我们需要
setup in the materials to tell it to use
在材质中进行一些简单的设置，告诉它使用
those colors that we painted so I'm
我们绘制的颜色。所以我
going to click here to go to the shading
点击这里进入着色
workspace and this is going to go into
工作区，这将进入
the Shader editor and we need to add a
着色器编辑器。我们需要给鱼添加一个
material to the fish so we'll just click
材质，所以我们点击
on new here to add a new material and
这里的“新建”来添加一个新材质，在
here I can just type in fish just to
这里我输入“fish”来
call this fish so then these here are
命名这个材质。 这些是
the Shader nodes if you don't know how
着色器节点。如果您不知道如何
to use the procedural Shader nodes I
使用程序着色器节点，我
have lots of tutorials on how to use the
有很多关于如何使用
Shader nodes you can of course check out
着色器节点的教程，当然您可以查看
my blender for complete beginners
我的Blender完全入门
tutorial series and you can also check
教程系列，也可以
out my blender beginner fundamentals
查看我的Blender入门基础
playlist where I have many different
播放列表，其中包含许多关于
videos on different parts of blender but
Blender不同部分的视频。但
this is basically the principal Shader
这里基本上是主着色器。
if I hold down the Z button and move my
如果我按住Z键并将
mouse into the material preview this is
鼠标移到材质预览中，这就是
the Shader so you can see I can like
着色器。您可以看到我可以
change the roughness and you can also
更改粗糙度，也可以
like change the color but what I'm going
更改颜色。但我要做的
to do is just add in a node here which
是在这里添加一个节点，其中
has the color data that we painted so
包含我们绘制的颜色数据。所以
I'll press shift a for the ad menu and
我按Shift+A打开菜单，
and I'm going to start to type in
然后开始输入属性。
attribute and we can go here to the
我们可以选择
color attribute so we'll click on the
颜色属性，所以我们点击
color attribute drop it here and then if
颜色属性并将其拖放在这里。然后，如果
I click on this right here we can choose
我点击这里，我们可以选择
this color and this is the one that we
这个颜色，这就是我们
painted now we can take these wires here
绘制的颜色。现在我们可以把这些
and I can plug the color wire into the
线连接到
base color so instead of it using the
基础颜色上，这样它就不是使用
base color which is one single color
基础颜色（一个单独的颜色）了。
it's now going to use the colors that we
现在它将使用我们
painted in the painting sculpt mode so I
在绘画雕刻模式下绘制的颜色，所以我
can now click back here to go to the
现在可以点击这里返回
layout and then we'll just do a few
布局界面，然后我们做一些
things to make this look really nice in
调整，让它在3D视图中看起来更美观。我
the 3D view so I'll click here to go to
点击这里进入
the render properties and I'm going to
渲染属性，
scroll down here and on the color
向下滚动到颜色
management I'm going to click on the
管理，点击“
look here and change this to very high
外观”，将其更改为“非常高
contrast to kind of pop out the colors
对比度”，使颜色更加突出，
and make them look more saturated and
饱和度更高。
then if you just want to change the
如果您只想更改
viewport lighting you can click on this
视口照明，可以点击这里的
drop down here if you're in the material
下拉菜单。如果您处于材质
preview mode you can click around here
预览模式，可以点击这里，
and then you can click on this here this
然后点击这个
little circle and this is going to give
小圆圈，它会显示
you some different hdri lightings so you
一些不同的HDRI照明，您
can change this around to something that
可以将其调整到合适的效果。
turn the strength down if you don't want
如果您觉得照明太强，也可以降低强度。
it to be quite that strong and then one
最后，
more thing you can do if you select the
如果您选择
fish and click here to go to the
鱼并点击这里进入
materials you could make the fish look a
材质，可以通过向下拖动粗糙度来使鱼看起来
bit more reflective by dragging this
更具反射性。
roughness down and now you can see the
现在…… 可以看到
fish looks a bit more shiny and
鱼看起来更有光泽，更有
reflective and there we go we now have a
反射效果了。好了，我们现在就得到了一个
nice cute stylized 3D fish sculpt so
漂亮可爱的3D鱼雕塑。
that's going to wrap it up for this
本教程到此结束，以上就是
do sculpting in blender for beginners so
Blender雕刻入门的基础知识。
I hope you enjoyed this video I hope you
希望你喜欢这个视频，也希望它对你有所
found it helpful and thank you for
帮助。感谢
watching and you can also purchase the
观看！你也可以
finished project files for free on my
在我的Gumroad商店和Patreon页面上免费购买完成的项目文件，
links are in the description and also my
链接在视频描述中。我的
gumroad store and patreon Page are great
Gumroad商店和Patreon页面也是
ways to help support this Channel and on
支持本频道的绝佳途径。在
my gumroad store and patreon page you
我的Gumroad商店和Patreon页面上，你
can get access to lots of blender
可以获取大量的Blender
content like 3D models and assets
内容，例如3D模型和素材、
tutorial files artwork project files
教程文件、艺术作品、项目文件、
procedural materials geometry node
程序材质、几何体、节点
modifier setups and lots more blender
修改器设置等等。
patreon page and if you really enjoy
如果你真的喜欢
sculpting and you want to get more into
雕刻，想要更深入地学习
sculpting and blender and learn more
Blender
about sculpting and you can check out my
雕刻，可以查看我的
blender sculpting tutorial playlist on
Blender雕刻教程。
my YouTube channel where I have many
我的YouTube频道上有一个播放列表，里面有很多
more sculpting tutorials so I have
雕刻教程，包括
specific videos on some of the tools and
一些工具和
some of the workflows and then I also
工作流程的专门视频，还有
have some follow along tutorials where
一些跟练教程，教
you can learn how to sculpt some
你如何雕刻
different sculptures and if sculpting is
不同的作品。如果
something that you really want to get
你真的想
good at and something that you really
精通雕刻，并深入学习，
want to get into then I can highly
我强烈
recommend checking out CG boost Master
推荐CG Boost的
sculpting and blender course that's a
Blender大师雕刻课程。这门课程内容非常
really big course and it goes into so
丰富，讲解也更加
much more detail and you'll learn so
详细，能让你学到
much more more about sculpting and
更多关于雕刻和
blender and if you purchase it through
Blender的知识。如果你通过
my affiliate link then I'll earn a small
我的推广链接购买，我会获得少量
commission but with no extra cost to you
佣金，但你无需支付任何额外费用。
so I hope you enjoyed this video and
希望你喜欢这个视频，
thank you for watching
感谢观看！